we did not attack We have our own
мы не напали Мы у нас получается сво
special military operation we are
специальная военная операция
liberating our lands which PP stop stop What
освобождаем свои земли которы ПП стоп
lands in the Kharkov
стоп Какие вы земли в Харьковской
region are you
области
liberating yours Which ones are yours which used to be
освобождаете свои Какие свои которые
ours Which ones used to be Well,
были раньше нашими Какие раньше Ну
back in the days of the tsars Which tsar Do you
ещё во временах царей Какого царя Ты
know the tsar but
знаешь царя да
not the tsar what was it
не царь как она
called it flew out of my head
называлась се с головы
let's have a normal conversation what
вылетело давай нормально пообщаемся
come on what in the
что давай что в
hospital no on this like on
госпитале нет на это в этом как е в
vacation understood And what are you lying in your pants and not
отпуске понял А что в штанах лежишь не
taking off no these are not pants this is a body Ah
снимаешь не это не штаны это нателка А
understood No I thought maybe the wounded can't take off your
понял Не я думал может раненый не можешь
leg well take off your pants no body
снять ногу ну снять штаны нет нателка
understood but on vacation Where did you
понял а в отпуске Откуда
come from on vacation Well with this from military
приехал в отпуске Ну с это с боевых
operations Well in what direction
действий Ну на каком направлении
were you on Kupyansk about there they battered you
был на купянском о там потрепали вас
like well yes Well they battered you well not bad Well no well both sides are
вроде хорошо да Ну потрепали да неплохо
standing like
Вот не ну и та и та строна стоит как бы
well neither one nor the other is surrendering and how did you
ну не сдаётся ни та ни другая а ты как
end up in the war at all I
попал на войну вообще я контракт
signed the contract when oh another 7 months ago
подписал когда ой ещ ещ 7 месяцев назад
and
а
why was it already clear
зачем уже было видно
that no well you know I basically
чтот не ну знаешь Я в основном контракт
signed the contract  not to go there Oh
подписал не для того чтобы там пойти Ой
there well as some you know
там ну как некоторые знаешь
say
говорят
they need to move away I no they
надо чтобы они отошли Я нет больше всего
paid the most they pay me 300,000 a month
заплатили вот мне платят 300.000 в месяц
3,000 dollars Well well that's a month Well how
3.000 долларов Так ну вот в месяц Ну как
would you know for
бы знаешь за
these not for half a year not even a month For
эти не не за полгода даже месяца За
four I already bought myself a car and a house
четыре Я уже себе и машину купил и дом
Yeah Well and they also gave you
приобрёл Угу Ну и тебе ещё дали за
some money for signing the contract yeah yeah and
подписание контракта сколько-то да да
also for signing the contract for
ещё и за подписание контракта за
signing How much did they give 5 million 5 million
подписание Сколько дали 5 лямов 5 лямов
is 50,000 dollars
- это 50.000 долларов
Yes I just don't know the rates up to 100
Да я просто не знаю расценки до на 100
for 100 you need to get yes of course it turns out that is
на 100 надоть да то конечно получается
you went I understand correctly that
то есть ты пошёл я правильно понимаю что
you went to kill people in Ukraine to
ты пошёл убивать людей в Украину чтобы
buy yourself a house a car so you understand I The
купить себе дом машину так понимаешь я
point is I don't
Смысл в том я их не
kill them Yeah you're surprised Yeah you're surprised I
убиваю Да ну ты удиви Да ты удивлён я
see I don't kill them explain I I
вижу я их не убиваю объясни Я я
understand well I think you will understand now I
понимаешь ну я думаю ты Сейчас поймёшь я
only destroy equipment
только уничтожаю технику
Yeah You understand Who am I Yeah
Угу Ты понял Кто я Да
no well I destroy equipment  equipment roughly
нет ну технику я уничтожаю технику грубо
speaking I sit for example in one place and
говоря я сижу к примеру на одном месте и
destroy equipment 15 km away from
уничтожаю технику за 15 км от
me I am not a military man I don't know what it is I
меня я не военный я не шарю что это
fly on drones But I understood on a drone and it
такое на дронах летаю А на дроне понял и
turns out Well, someone is sitting in equipment the
получается Ну так в технике кто-то сидит
same way Well, in equipment that's right Yes You
также Да ну в технике правильно Да Ты
went to kill as if your country attacked
пошёл убивать как бы твоя страна напала
Ukraine and you went Why did you attack
на Украину и ты пошёл Почему напала
wait well attacked under well Kupyansk
подожди ну напала подо ну купянское
direction what country is this Kupyansk Yes it's
направление это какая страна Купянск Да
Ukraine Well Ukraine Well, you you
это Украина Ну Украина Ну вот вы вы
invaded Ukraine and destroy
вторглись в Украину и уничтожайте там
equipment of people there for money Well, look I
технику людей за деньги Ну смотри я
destroy I receive an order to destroy
уничтожаю мне приходит приказ уничтожить
equipment only if When our
технику только в том случае Когда наш
intelligence officer sees that this equipment is
разведчик видит то что эта техника
shooting at our
стреляет в нашу
super super that's right Yes but it shoots
супер супер правильно Да но она стреляет
in your direction Why Because it is
в вашу сторону Почему Потому что она
defending itself Well that's right Well, we are
защищается Ну правильно Ну мы же на
standing still it doesn't matter you are standing still
месте стоим неважно стоите Вы на месте
You attacked you attacked we didn't attack We have our own
Вы напали вы напали мы не напали Мы у
special military
нас получается сво специаль военная
operation we are
операция
liberating our lands cop stop stop
освобождаем свои земли коп стоп стоп
What lands are you liberating in the Kharkov region yours What
Какие вы земли в Харьковской области
yours would have been
освобождаете свои Какие свои бы
What before Well,
Какие раньше Ну
even in the times of the
ещё во временах
tsars of what tsars  isto history history
царей каких царей исто история история
Which king Do you
Какого царя Ты
know the king No,
знаешь царя
not the king, what was it
Да не царь как она
called, it
называлась с головы
flew out of my head Peter I Under Peter I the Kharkov
вылетело Пётр I при Петре I Харьковская
region was not part of Russia No, wait,
область не входила в Россию Нет подожди
I'll tell you You just asked which kings You
я тебя Ты просто спросил каких царей Ты
know, not the kings Under which
знаешь не прих при ках царях При каком
king the Kharkov region was part of
царе Харьковская область входила в
Russia no I won't tell you that
Россию не Вот этого я тебе не скажу Ну
Well, for example, Catherine
вот к примеру Екатерина
I gave away some lands There the
I земли что-то Там
lands that were
подарила те Земли которые были
ours Who else is there Peter I
нашими Кто там ещё Пётр
look look Kharkov region Kuns
смотри смотри Харьковская область кунс
were never in Russia this is later Lenin
никогда не были в России это потом Ленин
when Lenin came Yes, he like took Ukraine
когда прил Ленин Да он типа взял Украину
into the Soviet Union and that's it And before that, like
в Советский Союз и всё А до этого типа
Which king, tell me Which king built
Какой царь скажи Какой царь построил
Kharkov, don't look, he took Ukraine The
Харьков не смотри он взял Украину
Soviet Union is right And what does
Советский Союз правильно А что хочет
Zelensky want to do, he's a cold
сделать Зеленский он хол не Подожди
Wait, wait So, stop, so Kharkov Which king
подожди Так стоп так Харьков Какой царь
created Kharkov Iku didn't create I mean
создал Харьков ику не создал я те имею в
captured that is Look No, according to
виду захватили то это Смотри Не ну по
history It was a Polish city Kharkov and
истории Это был польский город Харьков и
Kupyansk - it's a Polish city it was the
Купянск - это польский город это была
Polish-Lithuanian Commonwealth the Poles built yes
реч реч посполитая поляки построили да
forester Listen, did you capture this Polyakov,
лесница Слыш а этот Поляков не
Starke Well, that is, you say that you are
старке Ну то есть ты говоришь что вы
liberating the Kharkov region there
освобождаете там харьковскую область
because these were your lands under the tsars
потому что это ваши земли были при царях
under which
при каких
tsars I heard the
царях слышал
land there something is quiet far away the microphone you
зем там что-то тихо далеко микрофон ты
you Repeat this is not our
ты Повтори это не наши
land wait If these are not your lands
зем подожди й Если это не ваши земли
why are you attacking them then Well,
зачем вы тогда на них нападает Ну потому
because the course
что курс
was attacked you attacked the Kharkov region
напали вы в харьковскую область напали
back in the second year when there
ещё в два втором году когда никакого
was no Kursk Come on, you say not the one
Курска не было Давай ты говори не тот
who is broadcasting there And you I am talking to you here
кто там вещает А ты Я с тобой говорю вот
[ __ ] in the year they started bombing Kharkov
сри в году начали бомбить Харков
in the company of Wagner in the year PPP So you
в компании Вагнера в году ППП Так ты
only 7 months ago Signed a contract
только 7 месяцев назад Подписал контракт
said so this is the second contract And so so And how did
сказал так это второй контракт А так так
you end up in Wagner in the year also
А как ты в Вагнер попал в году также
also went as a volunteer when when you
также пошёл добровольце когда когда ты
Signed a contract in the second year Well,
Подписал контракт в д втором году Ну
when in what month In September And
когда в месяце каком В сентябре А уже
after the start with half a year as a lo s and
после начала с полгода как ло
there how much did they pay and there Well, exactly
с а там сколько платили а там Ну именно
per month I dont know They just gave me everything at the end
в месяц не знаю Мне просто всё в конце
at the end of the service how much did they give
отдали в конце службы сколько отдали
2700  2700 what two million 700 And how long did you
2700 2700 чего два ляма 700 А сколько ты
serve in Wagner six months six months 2700
служил в вагнере полгода полгода 2700
divided by 6 in short it comes out somewhere
делим на 6 короче это получается где-то
yes 400,000 something per month Well like
да по 400.000 чем-то в месяц Ну типа
if with these with entrance it is yes Ah so in
если с этими с входными это да Ай вот в
twenty-second year we were heading to
двадцать втором году мы направлялись в
Bakhmut so Bakhmut was taken So wait Well
бахмут так вот бахмут взяли Так подожди
so Bakhmut is also not this Polish
Ну так бахмут это тоже не это польский
city Well Polish city Polish Wait
город Ну польский город польский Подожди
Stop his Bakhmut Bakhmut was created by his
Стоп его бахмут бахмут был создал его
Polish king uh this how is he Boleslav
польский король ээ этот как он болеслав
Boleslav Bakhmutovsky He created the city
болеслав бахмутов ский Он создал город
named after himself Bakhmut in honor in honor of the
имени себя бахмут назвал в чести в честь
former he was yes And he created the city Bakhmut
быв он е был да И создал город бахмут
then according to
потом
this
по этому
according to the agreement with Brusko it was transferred to
по с бруско договору он был передан
Ukraine in deno the first year in de the first
Украине в дено первом году в де первом
year when Ukraine declared
году когда Украина провозгласила
independence from the Soviet Union Yes the
независимость от Советского Союза Да
official authorities of Poland concluded on the
официальные власти Польши заключили на
Zbruch River between the Khmelnytsky and
реке збруч между Хмельницкой и
Ternopil regions near Gorodok
Тернопольской областью возле Городка
Satanov concluded with Brusko the so-
Сатанов заключили с бруску угоду так
called agreement  Zbruch treaty on the transfer of
называемую збручский договор о передаче
Bakhmut to the total possession of Ukraine And what does
бахмута в всев нае владение Украины А
Russia have to do with it? Which king created
Россия тут при чём Какой царь создал
Bakhmut? Don't say that the goal was to create ba
бахмут те не говори что цель создал ба
So what are you for? What are you
Так а что же вы за что же вы
capturing? That's all That's all They go for the
захватывает вот и всё Вот и вся Идут они
money Yes, and
за бабки
then he got ahead in life, he kills
Да а тут он выбился в люди он убивает
people, and they pay him money for it, they pay
людей а ему за это платят бабло платят
money, he bought a car, an apartment, he's
бабло он купил машину квартиру он
happy, that is, Russia is
радуется то есть Россия
such a country that a person has no
настолько страна что у человека в ней
options to buy a car and an apartment in it except to
вариантов купить машину и квартиру кроме
kill people in another country
как убивать людей в другой стране
Why in Europe, in America, people
нету почему в Европе там в Америке люди
can work and buy a car
могут все работать и купить машину
For Americans, it's generally a car, they bought a car
для Американ это вообще машина купил
for transportation, but for a Russian,
машину для передвижения а для россиянина
here I am killing people in another country I
вот Я убиваю людей в другой стране Я
bought a car
купил машину
[music]
[музыка]
and we need to show this to the whole world Let's
и надо показывать Это всему миру Давайте
like, subscribe, comment
лайк подписка комент
Oh, let's have a normal conversation,
О давай нормально пообщаемся
let's have a normal conversation Where are you
давай нормально Вы
from? Well, it doesn't matter where you are from, I'm
откуда Ну неважно откуда ну региона
just curious about the region, but I see that you are not
просто интересно но я так вижу вы не
Russian by your eyes Why, why not Russian? Well, by your eyes, you are not Russian?
русские по глазам Почему почему не
Well,
русские Ну по глазам не русские Ну
why not Russian? Well, Iko Buryatia Sakha
почему не русские Ну Ико Бурятия Саха
Tatarstan  Why are Russians Russians
Татарстан Почему русские русские
Siberians and Tatars in short I understood whether they are Tatars
сибиряки а татары короче понял татары ли
Bashkort Okay
башкорт Окей
good Why why not Russians Well by
хорошо Почему почему не русские Ну по
epicanthus damn by the eyes pom how well how are
эпикантус блин по глазам пом как ну как
you driving that no you are
ты что гонишь что
not
не ты не
Russian who are you And who are you I am a
рус ты кто такой А ты кто такой я
Jew a Jew
Еврей еврей
yes And where is your this what is his jargon there
да А где твой этот как его жаргон там
Jewish he has it
еврейский у него он есть
seems to be proof To a person who that you are not
походу доказва Челове который что ты не
Russian let's do without this as
русский давайте без это как
civilized cultured people yes
цивилизованные культурные люди да
let's do
давайте
it you guys I understand that some
так вы ребята Я так понимаю что какие-то
actors or
актёры либо
military men of course actors And what else are we
военные конечно актёры А что мы ещё тут
doing here Of course we are an actor Yes I understood understood
делаем Конечно мы актёра Да понял понял
and in short there is a good film the director
и короче есть хороший фильм режиссёр
is Robert Madyar he just
есть Роберт мадяр он как раз вот
uses his style of disposable
использует у него стиль одноразовых
actors I recommend you to sign up for one
актёров Я рекомендую вам к нему на одну
of the next episodes with him
из следующих серий
for
записаться для
what for what Well in order to
чего для чего Ну для того чтобы ну
act in a movie
сняться в кинематографе
And for what purpose SBO Thank you he is just
А для какой цели СБО Спасибо он просто
ce Well he makes great films his
це Ну он классные фильмы делает у него
style is called disposable actors that is
стиль одноразовые актёры называется то
in each episode he uses
есть он в каждой серии использует
actors who were not in the previous
актёров которых не было в предыдущей
episode that is he does not repeat And interesting
серии то есть не повторяет А интересно
Yeah  interesting yes he shoots objective
Угу интересно да сни снимает объективный
realism uh some horror films there
реализм ээ некоторые фильмы ужасов там у
he has there like Alya
него есть там про типа Аля
like Aliens Yes there are worms
как Пришельцы Да там черви у него есть
there he has all sorts of things like worms dig
там вот такое всякое там типа черви роют
all sorts of holes yes And in short they are
всякие там норы да А их короче ну
destroyed and these worms
уничтожают и эти черви
attack you how do you like such a tezi well
атакуют вам как нравится такой тези ну
now you are saying like normal
ты сейчас говоришь типа нормальные
Conversations something this I dont listen to this
Разговоры что-то это не слушаю этого
reasonable conversation with you is normal Well
разумного разговора с тобой нормально Ну
I am a cinematographer well you said that you are an
я кинематограф ну вы же сказали что
actor I am saying that there is just a director
актёр я говорю что как раз есть режиссёр
Robert Madyar now I watch him sometimes
Роберт мадяр сейчас я смотрю его иногда
on Syria you understand this Sarcasm was It was
на Сирий вот понимаешь это Сарказм был
sarcasm I mean I am not serious are you an
Это сарказм бы В смысле Не я серьёзно вы
actor or civil servants actors of course what to
актёр или служащие актёры конечно что
us and not Well here here many people just like well
нам а не Ну тут тут многие просто типа
dress like this as a military man to mow in
ну одеваются так под военных косят
short yes No I am not a
короче ну да Нет я не
SPO but you are really military yes then you will
СПО а то вы военные реально да то вам
definitely star in this in the series Mad you
полюбому сняться в это в сериале Мад
can yes Not there will be more than
можно да Не там е
once we will shoot a film its cool
будет ещё не раз снимем фильм прикольно
just simply it Well it seems to me that you
просто просто это Ну мне кажется что вы
would know this you know What kind of film will there be you
бы знаешь это знаешь Какой фильм будет
know what kind of brother  the film will be Kai
знаешь какой братишка фильм будет Кай В
Only old men are going to battle two there is one he has one he
бой идут одни старики два есть такой у
already has a cosplay for this the
него есть у него уже есть косплей на это
Hungarians have some there on these on e
у мадяр есть там такие на этих на э
crutches like They are going They are going in short and
костылях типа Идут Идут короче и там
something is happening to them there yeah And what do you
что-то с ними происходит да А ты что
want you what are you doing now what do you want to
хочешь ты что ты сейчас что хочешь нас
offend us or something Yes I am already
обидеть что ли или что Да я уже вас
offending you Well well you won't be able to do it already It
обижаю Ну ну у тебя это не получится уже
worked Yes it won't work everyone who knows
Получилось Да не получится все кто знает
about such Robert Hungarian has already laughed at you
к такой Роберт мадяр уже с вас поржали
Come on Glory to Ukraine You know why Because they
Давай Слава Украине Знаешь почему Потому
listened and didn't
что слушали и не
understand
понимали
actors this is in our concept Yes Robert
актёры это у нас в концепции Да Роберта
Madra using disposable actors fits in
мадра использование одноразовых актёров
just right
как раз
Salam aleikum
вписывается Салам алейкум
Why are you hiding your face what a
Что прячешь лицо что
coward no I understand Yes Russians and Chechens
трус нет понял Да русские и чеченцы не
should not hide their faces we must go to the
должны прятать лица мы должны идти к
enemy where are you now I was in the Kursk
врагу навы где сейчас Я был в Курской
region now in the GUR Messi on rotation where are you And where
области сейчас в ГУР Месси на ротации ты
were you in Donetsk Yes there is still in Donetsk yes
был на Донецком Да там ещ на Донецком да
And where is the rotation
А где на ротации
now Belgo
сейчас белго
Bel
бел
rotation we were taken to Gudermes there on the
ротация нас в Гудермес отвели там на
crossing  staffing a little battered
пере укомплектования немного потрепала
us in the Kursk region and I
нас на Курской области
myself am from
у а сам родом
where from
откуда с
Russia We are all from Russia some city
России Мы все с России город какой
Far East wai myself I have
Дальний Восток вай сам Есть у меня
brothers in
братья в
Khabarovsk understood And who are you by
Хабаровске понял А ты кто по
military specialty look at the stew I watch
военной смотри по рагу смотрю
Independent Well as if I now no longer have
Независимый Ну как бы я сейчас нет уже
Ichkeria For now yes but we honor the flag because
Ичкерии Пока да но флаг мы чтим потому
my father fought then against the
у меня отец воевал тогда против
federal troops Akhmat Kadyrov also
федеральных войск Ахмат Кадыров тоже
fought against the federal troops and that
воевал против федеральных войск и что
now Hero of
сейчас Герой
Russia and why don't you like it so much do you
России а что теб так не нравится ты
think Chechens are not like that
считаешь чеченцам не такими какими-то
and the Union signed an agreement then
а союзки соглашения подписали потом
all this won the first company and the
всё это первую компанию выиграли и
second
вторую
too Why how did they take Chechnya How
тоже Почему как забрали Чечню Как потому
because they agreed Yes that Akhma Akhmat will be
что договорились Да что ахма Ахмат будет
Kadyrov will be president And then they will
Кадыров будет президентом А и тогда
stop all this and sort of make peace so that
остановят это всё и как бы помирятся
Russia will pay us money and
чтобы Россия будет платить нам деньги и
Russia is still paying and pouring into
Россия же до сих пор платит вливает в
Chechnya How much money as if We
Чечню Сколько денег как если Мы
lost and Russia feeds Chechnya you
проиграли а Россия кормит Чечню ты
watched how Grozny was rebuilt
смотрел как Грозный отстроили просто
our elders simply got together and discussed this
собрались наши старейшины и обсудили это
proposal Yes that they will stop the war  we will
предложение Да что остановят войну мы
be like a part of Russia but we
будем как бы в составе России но у нас
will have our own powers they
будут полностью свои полномочия нас
will pay us and we will be Russia
будут платить нам и мы будем Россия не
will not interfere in our internal And that's
будет вмешиваться в наши внутренние И
all And why are we an hour yes look a Chechen
всё И почему мы час да посмотри чеченец
comes to the Rostov region Everyone is on
приезжает в Ростовскую область Все на
duty like that Oops And no one will
струнка так Опа стоят А к нам никто не
come to us even the feds don't come to us we have
приедет даже федералы не идут к нам у
Ramzan Akhmatovich he does everything
нас Рамзан Ахматович он всё делает
so it turns out how we maintain our
поэтому получается как мы держим свои
order we are actually independent Well how are we
порядки мы фактически независимые Ну как
dependent according to the Constitution you are a subject of the
Конституции зависим ты субъект
Russian Federation right right
Российской Федерации правильно правильно
Look look how according to the Constitution We are in
Смотри смотри как по Конституции Мы в
Russia yes In fact in fact yes Russia
России да По факту по факту да Россия
pays us Russia does not influence anything
платит нам Россия не влияет ни на что
inside here everything is here Ramzan Kadyrov
внутрь тут всё вот Рамзан Кадыров с
personally has agreements with Putin
Путиным лично имеет договорённости Да
Yes Chechnya is not formally separating and
вот Чечня формально не отделяется а
Russia is not interfering in Chechnya it only gives
Россия не лезет в Чечню только отдаёт
money and that's all look how many Russians are
деньги и всё посмотри сколько русских
left after this war in general you
осталось после этой войны вообще у нас
won't find a Russian here now we used to have them
русского сейчас не найдёшь
now with me now anyone will come n yes
сейчас с я сейчас любой заедет
come Yes as a tourist but will not
н да заедет Да как Турист но не
stay You understand it will be uncomfortable for him to live here it will be
останется Жить тут понимаешь ему
very
некомфортно будет очень
uncomfortable look how  this uh Ramzan
некомфортно посмотри как этот ээ Рамзан
Kadyrov New Year children who were born
Кадыров Новый год дети которые родились
who will be named after the Chechen
которых назовут имя именем чеченских
heroes
героев
Baysangur Shamil
байсангура Шамиля
uh Imam Shamil and then beh the second then
ээ Имама Шамиля и дальше бех второя то
gave money gave money a stipend To these
дал деньги дал деньги стипендию Этим
women who gave birth to children and named them
женщинам которые родили детей и назвали
you know this we now have
именами ты это знаешь у нас сейчас у нас
district courts there were still Soviet
районные суды были ещё советские
names Ramzan Akhmatovich renamed
названия Рамзан Ахматович переименовал
everything to Chechen names how is this
всё в чеченские названия как это
decommunization how
декоммунизация как
Uh we Uh-huh Everything we have is ours your money
Ух мы Угу Всё у нас своё деньги ваши
only Yes many of ours died then
только Да много наших тогда полегло
ours but we took yours too then our
наших но и ваших мы забрали потом наши
elders said yes we can
старейшины сказали да мы можем большой
achieve with great bloodshed that Russia will
кровью добиться того что Россия вообще
leave altogether but it is better to conclude a temporary fact with it now and what
уйдёт но лучше с ней сейчас заключить
happened Yes we have visas
временный факт и что Получилось Да визы
from Russia No we enter Russia
у нас с России Нет мы въезжаем в Россию
wherever you want our guys hold
куда хочешь наши ребята держат
security agencies so to speak there
силовые агентства так сказать там
security agencies St. Petersburg Moscow all these
охранные агентства Питер Москва все эти
cities Do you understand what he is talking about in
города Ты понимаешь о чём он в
Valbury police let's say how to
валбери милиция допустим как
live by Russian law
жит российским зако
look at this guy from Volgograd
посмотри вот этот парень из Волгограда
Nikita Zhuravel burned  Koran that
Никита Журавель жёг Коран что Ему
Russian laws helped him Ramzan
помогли российские законы приехал Рамзан
Akhmatovich arrived took him from the Volgograd pretrial detention center they
Ахматович забрал его из СИЗО
brought him to
Волгограда его привезли в
Chechnya baby Ramzan Akhmat arrived This is
Чечню малыш Рамзана Ахмата пришёл Это
Adam Kadyrov 15 years old under What laws are you
Адам Кадыров 15 лет по Каким законам ты
talking about What laws he is like a
говоришь по Каким законам он его как
sack just as you understand for someone
мешок просто как понимаешь чтобы кто-то
Russian to take a Chechen and beat him like that on
русский взял забрал чеченца и так бил на
camera and post it on the Internet It is
камеру и выкладывал в интернет Это
unthinkable And our head of the Republic
немыслимо А у нас глава Республики в
posted it on Instagram and we are respected and
Инстаграме выложил и нас уважают и
feared no one of you uttered a peep that's why yes that's
боятся никто не пикнул из вас поэтому
why I can hang an
так да поэтому я могу повесить флаг
Ichkerian flag no one of the Russians will tell me
ичкери мне никто не скажет из русских
Ramzan Akhmatovich will ask Why did I hang it
Рамзан Ахматович спросит Почему повесил
I will say my father fought Okay
я скажу у меня отец воевал Окей
And that's
И
all And what did you finish off
всё И что вы
I agree with you now in many ways
добили я с тобой сечас соглашусь тут
In
много во многом В
what Yes
чём Да
how did it happen that the Russians As you
как так получилось что русские Как вы
say won the war But in fact we
говорите выиграли войну А по факту мы
Chechens have a higher status in Russia than
чеченцы по статусу в России выше чем
you Yes you are not by status
вы Да ты не по статусу
Above look I explain a Russian commits a
Выше смотри объясняю русский делает
crime Yes they take him to the
преступление Да его берут в
dark  our guys did Ramzan Akhmatovich
тму наших парней делали Рамзан Ахматович
we take him to Chechnya for
мы его забираем в Чечню на
re-education And that's it And how he is re-
перевоспитание И всё И как пере
educated He walks normally In the
воспитывается Ходит нормально В
storm of 2016 I was in prison, in short, but that
гроз 2016 году я сидел короче но такой у
was his Islam In short, he had
него и был Ислам Короче у него была
article
статья
205 He was sent from Grozny to
205 Он был с Грозного отправлен в
Transbaikalia He was in prison What was he in prison for
Забайкалье Он сидел в зака у ты За что
first I don't know these numbers I haven't been
сидел перво Я не знаю номера эти я не
in prison and
сидел а 205 это
what is 205 Well, yes Because that's the
что Ну так да Потому что вот
only thing they were in prison This is who is for whom
Единственное сидели Это кто за кто
against Ramzan
против Рамзана
Akhmatovich in 2012 from Chechnya he was
ахматовича в 2012 году с чеч был
sent to
отправлен в Забайкальский
Transbaikalia only if
край только если за
he steals for extremism at all not
экстремис он украдёт вообще не
[laughter]
[смех]
San this is just a divine video he is
Сань это просто Божественный ролик он
such I agree with you
такой я с тобой соглашусь
this is just brutal like subscribe
это просто жесть лайк подписка
comment Oh let's talk don't
комент О давай поговорим не
switch Yes let's talk Are you a
Переключайся Да давай поговорим Ты
military man or just dressed up like that a military man
военный или просто вырядился так военный
just a lot just yurts so and so
просто много просто выр так
just came to talk to me What kind of a
так-то просто зашёл поговорить с ми Что
catori of a square is this KNU this is a pagan
катори угольника это КНУ это языческий
symbol representing three worlds the world of gods the world of the
символ обозначает три мира мир богов мир
living and the world  dead you are some kind of
живых и мир мёртвых ты типа какой-то
Russian nationalist Well yes yes Understand Listen
русский националист Ну да да Поня Слушай
if a Russian nationalist Good
вот если русский националист Хороший
question how do you feel about the fact that in
вопрос как ты относишься к тому что в
modern Russia Chechen Kadyrov have a
современной России чечен Кадыров имеют
higher position Than Russians We
высшее положение Чем русски
need to decide somehow to
Нужно решать как-то с ней
fight it ways while the war is going on I haven't
бороться способы пока идт война я ещ не
figured it out myself yet so it's bad Armed Forces and
придумал сам поэтому это плохо ВС так и
before the war somehow there were no ways now
до войны как-то способов не было сейчас
look during the war Yes Chechens
во смотри во время войны Да чеченцы
only strengthened their positions now even
только усилили свои позиции теперь даже
this one like him who Milchakov Yes
этот как он который мильчаков Да на
Aladdin went to the fan of lapta Like
поклонник к лапте аладино
that bosom So it turns out
пошёл Типа того лоне Так получается
like the titular nation yes
как титульная нация да
reptiles So what do Chechens have
пресмыкающиеся Так что у чеченцев есть у
you don't have for example if Russian guy
вас нет например если русского парня
Nikita Zhuravlya e Kadyrov takes to the season
Никиту журавля э Кадыров забирает в сезо
Grozny brings his boy and he
Грозного приводит своего малого и он его
beats him with his feet with his hands films him on video and
бьёт Ногами Руками снимает на видео и в
posts it on Kadyr's Instagram no one
Instagram Кадыра выкладывает никто и в
including You didn't open your mouth at Kadyrov
том числе Ты не открыл рот на Кадырова
everyone is silent That's how it turns out Well that's
все молчат Вот так и получается Ну так
understandable because we have a nation it is
Понятное дело потому что у нас нация она
not nationalized at  we have no
не национализированы у нас нет
self-awareness that is conditionally If you
самосознания то есть условно Если ты
see, well, a Tajik sees how a Tajik is being beaten by a
видишь вот ну таджик видит как избивают
crowd of Russians, he will naturally
таджика толпа русских он естественно за
stand up for him no matter how many of them there are
него заступится сколько бы их не было
If the Russians see How the Tajiks are a crowd of
Если русские увидят Как таджики толпой
one Russian, everyone will pass by there is no
одного русского все пройдут мимо нету
self-awareness there is nothing this is
самосознания нету ничего это
degradation this is the problem that Russian
деградация это проблема с которой и
nationalism is fighting against and even
борется русский национализм и даже
nationalists do not have any special self-awareness
националистов нету самосознания особого
so look here is an interesting
так вот так смотри вот интересный теперь
question now why then Russian nationalists
вопрос почему тогда русские националисты
instead of raising self-awareness
вместо того чтобы поднимать самосознание
yes instead of
да вместо того чтобы в средине России
defending their interests in the middle of Russia Yes national E
защищать свои интересы Да национальные Э
you are going to die in
вы идёте умирать в
Ukraine we are going to die in Ukraine Yes why don't Kadyrov's men die
Украину идём умирать в Украине Да почему
And you are
кадыровцы не умирают А вы
dying Because if we lose this war
умираете Потому что если мы эту войну
it will bring us even more
проиграем это наложит нас ещё ещё больше
shame than we have
позор чем мы имеем
now you understand what I'm talking about So stop stop
сейчас понимаете о чём я говорю Так стоп
again look why did you even
стоп ещё раз смотри зачем вы вообще
go to this war Personally, why did I go
пошли на эту войну Лично я зачем Пошёл
Yes I don't want Russia to go down in
Да я не хочу чтобы Россия вошла в
history as having lost
историю как проигравшая
again That is, you went just look
ещё раз То есть ты пошёл просто смотри
your country started  a senseless war and
ваша страна начала бессмысленную войну и
you went so that Russia simply does not
ты пошёл чтобы Россия просто не
lose yes yes that is look after the
проиграла да да то есть смотрите после
war people will not go into
войны люди не будут вдаваться в
details who supported whom they will
подробности кто кого поддерживал они
simply label the entire Russian nation as
просто повесят на всю русскую нацию
losers I don't need this And
ярлык проигравших Мне это не нужно А
why on the Russian nation on all Russians
почему на русскую нацию на всех россиян
Chechens Kadyrovites Yes on all Russians
чеченцев кадыровцев Да на всех россиян
That is we will all get it But
То есть это нам всем достанется Но
since the Russians will get it I went
поскольку достанется русским пошёл и я
accordingly So now look I
соответственно Так теперь смотри я не
can't understand Kadyrov It is most likely that they will
могу понять Кадыров Это скорее всего
also become separatists
также станут сепаратистами в скором
soon Therefore look you
времени Поэтому вот вот смотри ты же
see how they pump Chechnya with these weapons
видишь как накачивают Чечню этим оружием
Yes how the fighters how organized Akhmat is there
Да как бойцы насколько рованный Ахмат
how many tens of
там сколько у него там несколько десятки
thousands of fighters he has sitting in Chechnya
тысяч бойцов сидят в Чечне
yes this is the future just like Dudayev was a
да это же будущее также как Дудаев был
general in the Soviet Army then Oops And
генералом Советской Армии потом Опа И
now the leader of the
вот уже Лидер
national liberation movement you
национально-освободительного движения тя
Chechen
чеченская
company And look and all the Russian commanders are
компания А смотри а русских командиров
being removed Yes Utkin was removed Prigozhin was
всех убирают Да Уткина убрали пригожина
removed who is there from the Russian
убрали кто вот есть из русских
commanders Well there is left  Melkov in about
командиров Ну остался Мельков ин про
from the regular troops there are Russian officers
из регулярных войск там русские офицеры
Well and then Well they too all prog essentially would be
Ну и то Ну они тоже все прог по сути бы
so heavy here I am from all the
тба настолько тяжёлая вот я из всех
Russians Yes whom I know independent This is
русских Да которых знаю независи Это
Denis Kapustin
Денис Капустин
Rex Denis Kapustin Well you know killing
Рекс Денис Капустин Ну знаете убивая
Russians It seems to me that Russia is not particularly saved
русских Мне кажется Россию особо не спа
Why Here is the Russian volunteer
Почему Вот русский добровольческий
corps it is fighting for the freedom of Russia for the
корпус он как раз борется за свободу
freedom of Russians in
России за свободу русских в
Russia he says that he is fighting You
России он так говорит что он борется Вы
understand that killing Russians did
же понимаете то что убивая русских
not
Россию не
save Russia look again the Russian
спас ещё раз смотри русский
volunteer corps is fighting together with the
добровольческий корпус воюет вместе со
Slavs with the Ukrainians Yes against
славянами с украинцами Да против вот
this
этой
Chechen Kadyrovites inside Understandable They are
чеченской кадыровцев нутри Понятно Они
fighting oh They are fighting against the Chechen
воюют ой Они воюют против чеченской
Mafia And you know such a battalion named after
Мафии А знаете такой батальон имени
Maxim Krivonosov I dont know in which
Максима кривоносова не знаю в котором
former Ukrainian prisoners of war are fighting
воюет бывшие украинские военнопленные
Why did they decide to join our
Почему они решили присоединиться на нашу
ronu I saw this thing then The thing is that
рону Я видел эту штуку значит Дело в том
it was done in the media there it seems they
это медийно было сделано там вроде
wrote Maxim We havent seen it anywhere else
написали Максим Больше нигде не видели
Where did you run away everything Yeah
Куда ты убежал всё
thats how he sits in recognizes Well yeah
Ага вот так он сидит в признаёт Ну да
Karo Well yeah we  Chechens but I went so as
Каро Ну да мы чеченцы но я пошёл чтобы
not to lose that's all the only
не проиграл вот и всё единственный
normal Russian nationalists are the
нормальные русские националисты - это
Russian volunteer corps that is
русский добровольческий корпус который
now fighting against this Kremlin on the
сейчас воюет против этой кремлёвской на
side of Ukraine all the rest are these like
стороне Украины все остальные это вот
cops like Chechens
эти под ментовские под чеченские
such funny shots so eat
такие смешные кадры так ем
Hello dump Ukraine hero dump
Привет свалка Украине героем свалка
cool you have Nasira Handsome bro where are you
прикольный у тебя насира Красава братуха
from yes What does it have to do with it But it's just not I
откуда да При чём здесь Но а просто не я
think it was you who did the design rhinoplasty
думаю это ты дизайн сделал ринопластику
so Well, my
так
friend I have money I'll have an
Ну вот друган у меня деньги есть я
operation now and go
сейчас сделаю операцию и поеду
Listen you're sitting on the toilet
Слушай ты сейчас на унитазе сидишь
smoking I'm in the toilet Yes I'm sitting and smoking it's cool that
куришь я в туалете Да сижу курю
is you're sitting in the toilet
прикольно то есть ты сидишь в туалете
smoking At
куришь
home Well at home yes
Дома Ну дома
And what about you Well did you have some kind of
да А что у тебя Ну ты делал какую-то
plastic surgery or
пластическую операцию или
what do you mean
что в смысле
what kind of surgery you need to
какую
change it was done on purpose
нуно менял это так специально сделано
or is it a
или Это
defect No they didn't beat me It's just when in the
дефект Да не меня побили Просто когда в
village in the
деревне в
village 5 years ago I understood Well the doctor does
деревне 5 лет назад понял А ну врач не
n't straighten the nose
не ровняет нос
normally Well you need money everything
нормально Ну это же надо деньги всё
now you understand So what about there is no medicine in Russia
сейчас понимаешь Так а что в России нет
free well
бесплатной ну
such operations are only done for money
такие операции только за деньги делаются
And why did they
А за что
beat me up and Yes in the village there are drunk crosses you
побили а Да в деревне там пьяные кресты
know there are
знаешь там
drunk crosses What are well
есть кресты пьяные Что
crosses they are called
такое ну кресты это их называют
village crosses these are the crosses they are
деревенских вот эти кресты их
called in short I was
называют короче
driving near Khabarovsk to the village I myself live
ехал под Хабаровск в деревню Я сам живу
in
в
Khabarovsk I went to the village with a guy there
Хабаровске Поехал в деревню с парнем там
and at the disco These are the locals
и на дискотеке Вот вот эти местные
in short I understood And why Well that I
короче понял А за что Ну то что я
invited their girl to dance And
пригласил ихнюю девушку потанцевать А
how old are you I am
сколько тебе
50 years old 50 years old and you decided to go to a
Мне 50 лет 50 лет и ты решил на
disco with young girls Yes
дискотеку к молоденьким Да
go No well that was I am telling you
поехать Нет ну это было Я же тебе говорю
5 years ago Well you were 45 Yes you went
5 лет назад Ну тебе 45 было Да ты пошёл
to the
на
disco Well yes and there was a girl how old Well
дискотеку Ну да а там девчонка по
there were adults and all sorts of
лет Ну там и взрослые были и всякие
different Well and you invited the girl
разные Ну а ты девчонку пригласил
How old was she Well about 35 years old somewhere like that
Сколько ей лет было Ну лет 35 где-то вот
not a day such a woman is already
так нуже не денка такая уже женщина
normal yes a woman and what And how did it
нормально да женщина и что А как это
happen the villagers first came up
получилось деревенские сначала подошли
started saying did not invite or immediately
начали говорит не приглашали или сразу
knocked down without a
завалили без
word no they in short saw that I was dancing
слов нет они короче увидели что я танцую
with
с
her then I in short went outside
ней потом я короче вышел на улицу
they went out to smoke you say Listen, what are you
покурить они вышли ты говорит Слышь ты
inviting ours to
что наш приглашаешь
dance,
танцевать
city guy,
городской прикинь
guess what? In short, how they threw me some
Короче как накидали мне там
liches there I'm
личей я
there And you're in military uniform now, somewhere,
там А ты сейчас в военной форме где-то
you were at
ты был на
war Well, I came on vacation because I was wounded, I
войне Ну я по ранению приехал в отпуск
understood, in short,
понял короче
country guy, it's weak to knot you here
деревенский слабо тебя тут
Well, how did you get to war Well,
Ну а как ты на войну попал
how so? I went myself and went to
Ну как так Сам поехал пошёл деньги
earn money Well, like, you know, to
заработать Ну как бы знаешь
help mom with loans And what about mom's loans Well, she
что маме помочь с кредитами А что у мамы
just had a
кредитами Ну кредитов у неё было просто
lot of loans, and what did mom take
много а на что мама брала
loans for? Oh,
кредиты
in short, I don't know I did it for her business there, well, it's
короче не знаю я Это её на дела там ну
just that I had loans I know that mom had them
просто я вот кредиты Я знаю что у мамы
Well, what did she buy a house for, bought
были Ну на что она покупала дом покупала
real estate, there, shares, what did she take out on credit
недвижимость там акции что она в кредит
She spent more on her niece, what's the
брала Она больше на племянницу
joke, you know Well, she
тратила в чём прикол понимаешь
has a granddaughter,
Ну у неё есть внучка
yes, a granddaughter She has a granddaughter from my own brother,
да внучка Это от моего брата родного
she spent money on her Why not
внучка она на неё тратила деньги Почему
So, what did she take out on credit to
нет Так а что она брала в кредит чтобы
spend on her, I can't
на неё тратить не могу
understand
понять
All the iPhones there Wait, did
Айфоны там всю Вот эту вот шляпу подожди
I understand correctly that you went to war
я правильно понял что ты поехал на войну
to close  Mom's loans for granddaughters' iPhones
чтобы закрыть мамины кредиты на Айфоны
No, well, it's not just that
Да нет ну как бы там не только же это
iPhones were right
Айфоны были правильно
and
а
jeans No, we have everything we do
джинсы Да нет это у нас всё есть это
n't
ничего не
need anything and what was the amount of the loan Mom had,
надо а какая сумма кредита у мамы была
well, big Well,
ну большая Ну
what Well, five loans, you can
какая Ну пять кредитов вы сами можете
figure it out yourself, how much Well And for what amount, the
так понять скоко Ну А на какую сумму
main thing is, by the ass,
главно
50,000 each I
по п ой по 50.000
understood Well, you closed all her loans Yes,
там понял Ну ты закрыл её все кредиты Да
of course Of course, but she doesn't take new
конечно Конечно а она не берёт новые
loans No, that's it I told her don't
кредиты нет всё я ей сказал больше не
take any more loans, nothing, that's enough,
бери ни кредитов ничего всё хватит
listen, wait, uh, if you were wounded, they
слушай а подожди ээ если ты раненый тебе
paid you some money Well, of course,
выплатили какие-то бабки Ну конечно
how much Well,
сколько
3 million I got for the wound And where were you
Ну 3 млн Я получил за ранение А куда
wounded Well, I have two in the lung, a bullet wound in the shoulder
ранили Ну у меня два в лёгком пулевое в
blade and
лопатке и по ногам
shrapnel in the legs And how did they bury you Well, what is it
осколки А чем так тебя
called from this, AGS
этого как оно называется-то АГС
with GSA What is an
с гса Это что
automatic grenade launcher, I understood And
такое автоматический гранатомёт понял а
in what direction were
это на каком направлении
you I
тебя я на угледар
was in Ugledar Ugledar direction I was there So that was
был угледар направление я там был Так
when you were
это когда тебя
wounded on November 5, I
ранили 5 ноября
understood And when you went to war,
понял А когда на войну пошл
that is, in September  went and in
сентябре то есть в сентябре пошёл и в
November you were already wounded yeah Well yeah yeah it
ноябре у тебя уже ранили да Ну да да
turns out that way that is it turns out there was
получается так то есть получается
no training nothing they just
никакой учебки не было ничего только
took in short brought there and that's it yeah no
взяли короче туда привезли И всё да нет
Why was there a training we were somewhere there well for about
Почему была учебка мы где-то там ну
20 days probably at this training and
суток 20 наверное на этой учебке
then they took us
были а потом нас повезли
from Rostov they
вот с Ростова
took us there to
повезли вот туда на
Ukraine I
Украину
understood killed people and va And what's your name My name is
понял убивал людей а ва А Вас как зовут
Adrian Adrian Adrian a Nice to meet you My name is Dima Well
Адриан Андриан Адриан а Очень приятно
with normal people with
зовут Ну вот с нормальными с людьми вот
adequate people who are very pleasant to communicate
адекватными которые очень приятно обща
Thank you for being like that And what do you
Спасибо вам что вы такие есть А как вы
think why do people react to you so
думаете почему люди на вас так
inadequately
неадекватно
Well I don't know I don't know maybe
реагируют Ну не знаю не знаю может
because
потому что
you Well I would you know I
вы Ну я бы вы знаете
just
я просто
Let's not she talks about this topic
вот Давайте не будем она на эту тему
not Just let's this is an
разговаривает не Как раз будем это
interesting topic I
интересная тема вот как простой человек
want to talk to you as an ordinary person Yes it
хочу с вами поговорить Да вы ж
turns out you went to kill people in
получается вы пошли убивать людей в
Ukraine for money and wonder why
Украину за деньги и удивляйтесь почему
people
вас люди
hate you so much no And who hates us
ненавидят так нет А кто нас ненавидит
everyone loves to respect us who loves to
нас все любят уважать кто вас любит
respect you no one even villagers
уважать никто вас даже деревенский не
love and respect you Well it just happened that way
любят и не уважают Ну это так получилось
sorry it happened that way don't you want to
извините так получилось не хотите тут в
come to the disco here in Ukraine
Украину на дискотеку приехать
I won't go there anymore I have friends in the
я туда не поеду больше есть знакомые в
village who would like to do
деревне которые хотели бы
this Va No no thank you for your good
это Ва Не не спасибо вам за хорошее
understanding Everything you are a handsome man no no
понимание Всё вы красавчик не не
Switch Let's talk Yes it wasn't me who
Переключай Давай поговорим Да не я
rushed on That's how such
помчался дальше Вот так вот такие
contingents
контингенты за бабки
pay money for money and they go like that
и платят бабки и они идут вот так
subscribe to y Instagram I don't know why
подпишись на й Instagram Я не знаю для
it's for you why else you should watch
чого це тоб для чого ще тоб там дивитись
this face But for you one two or
на оцей фейс Але для тебе оди два або
three clicks and you try me and I'll be in
три клика а ты тримае мене и я буду к в
me there are a bunch of fouls and in me there will be a
мене там Купа фолов и в мене буде
cool naibro but cool video letter on y
класный найб ро но крут видео пись на й
inst
inst
Andriy that's
Андрий вот
how come I'm waiting for you
так давай я тебя чекаю